<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>History on Scoutmastercg.com Archive</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/history/</link>
    <description>Recent content in History on Scoutmastercg.com Archive</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/history/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Left Handshake</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/the-left-handshake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/the-left-handshake/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In his book, The Left Handshake Hilary St. George Saunders recounts the history of the Boy Scout Movement during the Second World War. 1939-1945. The book is available in PDF format&#xA;It is story of how scouts in occupied countries aided resistance  movements, maintained their troops and provided many public services often at great personal risk.&#xA;Poland, The Warsaw Uprising-&#xA;“After sixty-three days of bitter fighting, the insurrection was crushed, and on the 3 rd October, 1944, Warsaw fell for the second time. It was a cold, grey day, and in a house in Wilcza Street more than a hundred Scouts and Guides had gathered together. They knew it well, for some of them had helped in the hospital which had once been set up there. Now all that remained was a skeleton of scarred brick and mortar. A few were Scoutmasters who had commanded Scout units in the Home Army, but the great majority of that silent band was made up of boys and girls from the age of twelve upwards, all of whom had been heavily engaged in the fighting. They had carried messages, manned first-aid posts and fire parties, looked after homeless children, operated the Scout post office, printed and delivered newspapers, sung songs to divert terrified civilians hidden in the cellars during a bombardment, cooked for the army. There they stood in a semi-circle in the ruins of their city, and of their number forty that morning were decorated with the Cross of Merit and the Cross of Gallantry by the Chief Commissioner.”&#xA;Czechoslovakia-&#xA;“When, a few weeks before the end of the war the Germans carried out a mass migration of prisoners-of-war from east to west Czechoslovakia, Scouts near the German boundary kidnapped some sixty American prisoners-of-war who had arrived in an exhausted and starving condition, hid them in the woods and fed them till their compatriots arrived to find them alive and well, and conversing with their hosts by means of the American Indian sign language.”&#xA;Belgium-&#xA;“In the Liege district fourteen regular members of a Rover Crew, of the average age of twenty-two, set up one of the first information sections. Under cover of their Scouting activities they spied on the enemy and sent frequent reports by radio to the Allies. As the war progressed, they became expert in picking up and hiding supplies dropped to the Resistance by parachute. All these Rovers, of whom half paid for their patriotism with their lives, lived ” a tremendous adventure. ” Six escaped eventually to England, and of these, five joined the parachute troops and the other became a fighter pilot. At one time or another, ten of them were in the hands of the Gestapo, and four in those of the Spanish police. Including the seven who were executed, twelve went to concentration camps. At the end of the war the Minister of National Defence awarded a special decoration to be sewn on the flag of this splendid Troop, a unique distinction of which Belgian Scouts are justly proud.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Baden-Powell’s Outlook</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/baden-powells-outlook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/baden-powells-outlook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From the introduction:&#xA;For thirty yeas B.-P. contributed to the The Scouter notes and comments under the title &amp;ldquo;The Outlook.&amp;rdquo; The reader turned to these first, for he knew that he would there find encouragement, advice, and inspiration — all written in that very personal style which seemed like conversation. It was in this way that B.-P. trained those who were trying to carry out Scouting for Boys. Even when a training system was begun at Gilwell, these notes continued to be the chief means by which B.-P. could pass on his ideas and suggestions to the great army of Scouters everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Scouting Party</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/the-scouting-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/the-scouting-party/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have spent some memorable hours reading an advance copy of David C. Scott and Brendan Murphy’s new book The Scouting Party; a thoroughly researched, unflinching account of the founding and first decade of the BSA focused on  the lives of Earnest Thompson Seton, Robert Baden-Powell and Daniel Carter Beard. To my knowledge no one has so thoroughly analyzed the events and personalities involved in the founding of the BSA.&#xA;Histories of the BSA’s early years are typically encapsulations that may mention the differences between Seton, Beard and Baden-Powell in passing but The Scouting Party takes these matters up in incredible detail mappings out the troubled relationships of these three men through their letters and writings.&#xA;Rather than legend or hagiography this account is a work of careful reportage leading to a deeper understanding of the resilient and vital ideas created in this maelstrom of personalities.The result is is an inspiring account of ideas too big for any one man’s work. Despite their deep animosities for one another Seton, Powell and Beard ultimately created a remarkable organization. Clearly such an expansive vision would never have been realized without this dynamic tension.&#xA;The calculating hand of our first National Scout Executive, James West, and the somewhat mercenary machinations of publisher William D. Boyce weave through the narrative; two men who were crucial in bringing the work of far more visionary men to a practical reality.&#xA;We learn that Seton first envisioned the key concepts central to the basis of Scouting, Baden-Powell’s disciplined pragmatism was vital in bringing Seton’s somewhat woolly, inaccessible vision, to reality and Beard’s contributions were important to popularizing the movement in its formative years.&#xA;Each of these wildly divergent personalities were all key in forming the BSA as we know it. Having a measured, scholarly look at them in their own words as they forged this organization is incredibly valuable to our collective future. As we continue work to bring the promises of Scouting to reality we will encounter similar conflicts of style, personality and ideas. We can overcome these challenges and continue to weave together a vital, relevant, movement that answers the needs of the future while remaining firmly rooted in the vision of its creation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
