<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Philosophy on Scoutmastercg.com Archive</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/philosophy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Philosophy on Scoutmastercg.com Archive</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Productive Chaos</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/productive-chaos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/productive-chaos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over time, processes that seek to decrease entropy and create order are valued, but improving them gets more difficult as well. If you&amp;rsquo;re seeking to make the organized more organized, it&amp;rsquo;s a tough row to hoe.&#xA;Far easier and more productive to create productive chaos, to interrupt, re-create, produce, invent and redefine.&#xA;Seth Godin&#xA;Most of our work as Scoutmasters is like hiking a trail; start here and end up there. But things are not always that simple and organized. It&amp;rsquo;s not always a steady pace forward. We start, stop, regroup, retreat, advance, turn around, sit down, stand still, walk, run, crawl, limp, saunter; but at least most of the time we are doing something.&#xA;There&amp;rsquo;s a fair amount of productive chaos in Scouting (two words not often associated with one another). As a matter of fact we are specialists in productive chaos. Ideally our plans proceed in a straight, well disciplined line but that&amp;rsquo;s hardly ever the case.&#xA;Leadership is interrupting, re-creating, inventing and redefining. Yesterday&amp;rsquo;s plan may not work today. While the destination doesn&amp;rsquo;t change the way we get there does.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
