<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Scoutmastercg.com Archive</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Scoutmastercg.com Archive</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Test Post</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/test-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/test-post/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is my first post using VS Code.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Looking Ahead - Program Health</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/looking-ahead-program-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/looking-ahead-program-health/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fifth and final entry  in a series of thoughts about&#xA;looking ahead&#xA;.&#xA;Do we meet key indicators of effectively presenting our program?&#xA;The quality unit award (now the&#xA;centennial quality unit award&#xA;) has been the generally accepted standard for assessing unit program. Quality unit metrics do give some indications of the health of the program but we should take a closer look.&#xA;Quality unit metrics report adult leader training, youth recruitment and retention, parent participation, youth advancement, outdoor program participation, program planning. Meeting these indicators is somewhat like having a pulse – the unit is alive and kicking. Problem is a unit can meet these criterion with a program led and administered by adult leadership as well as one administered by youth leadership.&#xA;My choice of indicators would be a little different:&#xA;Patrol System&#xA;Patrols plan, purchase and prepare their own meals on camp outs.&#xA;The patrol leader was elected by the patrol.&#xA;Patrol leaders routinely sign off rank requirements.&#xA;Youth Leadership&#xA;Patrol leader&amp;rsquo;s council meets regularly&#xA;Senior patrol leader is elected by Scouts&#xA;Youth plan and present weekly Troop meetings and outings&#xA;Troops that meet these key indicators will almost certainly meet or exceed the quality unit metrics but not necessarily the other way round.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Model Scout Outing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/model-scout-outing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/model-scout-outing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“Scouting is Outing” and any lively, active Troop has an out-of-doors overnight experience planned every month of the year. Here’s a model of a typical outing that capitalizes on youth leadership and the Patrol Method.&#xA;Preparation&#xA;After the Patrol Leader’s Council (PLC) has developed a schedule of events for the year Scouts are detailed to set up the particulars of the trip. A few of the logistics are attended to by the adults ( securing campsites, various registrations etc.) but the PLC does the vast  majority of planning.&#xA;Patrols select a grubmaster for the trip who plans, purchases, packs and prepares their meals for the outing. Patrol Scribes collect fees and permission slips, the Patrol Quartermaster checks over the gear they will need and the Patrol leader administers all of these preparations.&#xA;The Senior Patrol Leader (SPL) and his cohorts form a transportation plan and oversee the preparations of the Patrols. The Troop Scribe collects money and permission slips from Patrol Scribes and develops a Troop roster for the outing. The Troop Quartermaster oversees the Patrol Quartermasters in preparing their gear. The SPL creates a schedule of activities for the outing.&#xA;Troop meetings leading up to the outing discuss any special skills or preparations for the trip. Ample time is scheduled for Patrols to complete their preparations.&#xA;Friday Night&#xA;The SPL and Patrol Leaders see that the Scouts have the proper personal gear and draw their Patrol and Troop gear from the Quartermaster, see that it is all packed properly, load everything up and move out.&#xA;Once they arrive at the campsite the SPL surveys the ground and assigns areas for each Patrol. He does his best to see that Patrols camp far enough apart to operate independently and that the adults are billeted far enough away to allow the Troop to function properly.&#xA;Before they head off to bed the PLC meets and reviews the schedule for the next day.&#xA;Saturday&#xA;The SPL and Patrol leaders get everyone up at the specified hour and breakfast is prepared. Patrols cook on their own and the Adults (who have planned and packed their own food) observe from a respectful distance.&#xA;Once breakfast is cleared away the day begins. The SPL and Patrol Leaders lead the Scouts through whatever activity is the order of the day. Adults may be invited to offer instruction (rarely) or asked to lend some oversight if the nature of the activity demands it. Otherwise the adults are pursing their own activities away from the Scouts.&#xA;Lunch and dinner happen much like breakfast as the day wears on.&#xA;The entire Troop gathers together for the first time Saturday evening. It may be a brief review of the day’s events, a campfire, a cracker-barrel or similar function.&#xA;Before everyone retires the SPL reviews Sunday’s activities with the PLC.&#xA;Sunday&#xA;Breakfast again prepared by the Patrols. It may be time to pack up, or to pursue some activity before returning home. On returning the SPL oversees the return of gear with the Quartermaster and Patrol Quartermasters.&#xA;After Action&#xA;The PLC meets to discuss the outing and what improvements can be made to their preparations or implementation. The gear is checked and cleaned if needed and the whole process is ready to begin again.&#xA;This model is just that, a model. It is based on the idea that Scouts must be given a very wide latitude to operate independent of adult interference yet with appropriate oversight. There is very little that the Scouts cannot do for themselves and they should be encouraged to do as much as they can manage.&#xA;Scouts cook on their own, camp on their own and pursue their activities on their own. Adults may be invited to participate actively, but unless they are they keep a respectful distance. How far distant? Ideally out of earshot and out of sight but close enough to be called upon if required.&#xA;Scouting is not a father or mother and son activity, not a family outing. Scouting happens when the Scouts lead themselves. When they are given autonomy and trust they respond by being responsible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ray Mears Building a Fire</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/ray-mears-building-a-fire/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/ray-mears-building-a-fire/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ray Mears&#xA;is an expert woodsman from southern Great Britan. I remember watching him on a U.S. cable network a few years ago. They can still be found on UKTV but I can&amp;rsquo;t find them in the U.S. Thankfully there are a number of clips on line like the one embedded above.&#xA;Mears is a serious student and teacher of bushcraft not a sensationalist unlike another British import whose show is (unfortunately) much more popular on U.S. televisions. He has authored many books available (with a selection of gear and related items at his website&#xA;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Recruiting Scouts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/recruiting-scouts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/recruiting-scouts/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We recruit Scouts from two general populations&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Webelos&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Everybody else&#xA;Webelos recruitment is simple to understand although it requires a fair amount of effort. Much has been written on Webelos transitions so I will not retrench the subject here. Here&amp;rsquo;s discussions of the&#xA;mechanics of the process&#xA;,&#xA;retaining the Webelos you recruit&#xA;and some notes on&#xA;transitioning Webelos leaders&#xA;.&#xA;By way of review -&#xA;Find all the Webelos Dens in your community within reasonable driving distance of your Troop.&#xA;Offer them support, camping opportunities and (perhaps most importantly) Den Chiefs.&#xA;Stay in touch with them throughout the entire year, don&amp;rsquo;t ever give up.&#xA;Recruiting Webelos takes more than it once did around here. There are fewer Webelos now than there were five or ten years ago. One of my assistant Scoutmasters maintains contact with three or four Cub Packs and we place as many Den Chiefs out there as we can in any den that wants them (Tiger through Webelos II). A Scout Troop may approach any Cub Scout Pack, there are no exclusive rights to a Cub Pack even if they share the same unit number as a Troop.&#xA;Recruiting everybody else is another story entirely.&#xA;What follows is based on twenty five years of attempting to recruit Scouts from the seventh through eighth grades. Recruiting Cub Scouts is much different and I don&amp;rsquo;t address it here.&#xA;We get one or two new Scouts a year by the force of gravity an active Scout-led program creates. They hear about the things their friends are doing and want to join in. We don&amp;rsquo;t actively recruit them, they just kind of show up.&#xA;I have tried the &amp;lsquo;cold call&amp;rsquo; methods (school visits, open houses) of recruiting Scouts for the general population over the years with very little success. Frankly I cannot recall recruiting more than one or two Scouts this way. It is tremendously little return for the effort and I don&amp;rsquo;t know as I can recommend them to you. There are more promising ways to boost your numbers.&#xA;In my experience we recruit one Scout from every;&#xA;Ten thousand boys who see a TV commercial, print ad or yard sign.&#xA;Five hundred boys who hear a direct mass appeal like School visits.&#xA;Ten or fifteen who are approached by a friend in Scouting.&#xA;Five or ten boys who&amp;rsquo;s parents are approached by a friend with a son in Scouting.&#xA;To my mind we should concentrate on the two most promising approaches.&#xA;One way our Troop will celebrate the centennial year of the BSA is by getting our Scouts to approach, one-on-one, 100 boys who are not Scouts.&#xA;We&amp;rsquo;re going to record this effort by asking our Scouts to keep track of three to five contacts they make over the course of the year. We will also actively encourage parents to contact their friends with Scout-aged sons.&#xA;Is it really that simple? I don&amp;rsquo;t really know, but we&amp;rsquo;ll soon see.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rigging a Tarp with Kevin Callan</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/rigging-a-tarp-with-kevin-callan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/rigging-a-tarp-with-kevin-callan/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Canadian canoeist and writer Kevin Callan shows how to rig a tarp -&#xA;The quality of your tarp and the skill of erecting one is more crucial&#xA;on a trip then a tent. Why? It’s all about group dynamics. During foul&#xA;weather the worst thing for a group of paddlers to do is to cram tight&#xA;inside a small tent to wait out the storm. It won’t take long before&#xA;even the best of friends begin to irritate one another. But under a&#xA;tarp, with a warm fire going and a cup of tea brewing, things don’t seem&#xA;so bad – as long as you’ve put the tarp up correctly…&#xA;Read the full post here&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tech Chip Card - a Good Start!</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/tech-chip-card-a-good-start/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/tech-chip-card-a-good-start/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s an interesting resource that offers a way to integrate Scouting with portable technology:&#xA;Tech Chip&#xA;Based on the Tote&amp;rsquo;n Chip concept. It was created by Troop&#xA;479 in Eden Prairie, MN. The troop has designed a training outline and&#xA;has wallet cards for purchase – see&#xA;Tech Chip Training Plan&#xA;for details.&#xA;Great minds travel on the same track. I&#xA;mentioned the need for something like this a year or so ago&#xA;and tried to interest one of my Scouts in drawing something up but he never got too far with the idea.&#xA;I think the folks at 479 have done a good job of identifying four simple guidelines;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Natural Genius of Children</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/the-natural-genius-of-children/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/the-natural-genius-of-children/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Thomas Armstrong, Ph.D. has more than thirty years of teaching experience from the primary through the doctoral level. He has authored many books related to learning and human development.&#xA;His writing on the&#xA;natural genius of children&#xA;is an excellent endorsement of Scouting;&#xA;Essentially, the real&#xA;meaning of genius&#xA;is to &amp;ldquo;give birth to the joy&amp;rdquo; that is within each child. Every child is&#xA;born&#xA;with that capacity. Each child comes into life with wonder, curiosity,&#xA;awe, spontaneity,&#xA;vitality, flexibility, and many other characteristics of a joyous being… These&#xA;youthful traits are&#xA;highly valued from an evolutionary perspective: the more species evolve,&#xA;the more they&#xA;carry youthful traits into adulthood (a process called &amp;ldquo;neotony&amp;rdquo; or&#xA;&amp;ldquo;holding youth&amp;rdquo;). It is imperative that we, as educators and parents,&#xA;help&#xA;preserve these genius characteristics of children as they mature into&#xA;adulthood, so those&#xA;capacities can be made available to the broader culture at a time of&#xA;incredible change.&#xA;First, and most importantly, adults need&#xA;to reawaken their&#xA;own natural genius—find within themselves the sourcewaters of their own&#xA;creativity,&#xA;vitality, playfulness, and wonder. For when children are surrounded by&#xA;curious and&#xA;creative adults, they have their own inner genius sparked into action.&#xA;Second, adults need&#xA;to provide simple activities to activate the genius of children.&#xA;Something as simple as a&#xA;story, a toy (Einstein said that a simple magnetic compass awakened his&#xA;love of learning&#xA;at the age of four), a visit to a special place, or a question, can&#xA;unlock the gates to a&#xA;child’s love of learning. Third, create a &amp;ldquo;genial&amp;rdquo; atmosphere at home or&#xA;school, where kids can learn in a climate free from criticism,&#xA;comparison, and pressure to&#xA;succeed. Treat each child as a unique gift from God capable of doing&#xA;wonderful things in&#xA;the world . Finally, understand that each child will be a genius in a&#xA;totally different&#xA;way from another child. Forget the standard I.Q. meaning of genius, and&#xA;use models like the&#xA;theory of multiple intelligences&#xA;to help kids succeed on their own&#xA;terms. By following&#xA;these simple guidelines for awakening each child’s natural genius, you&#xA;will be&#xA;contributing immeasurably to the welfare of your children and to the&#xA;world they will&#xA;inherit someday.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Left Handshake</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/the-left-handshake/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/the-left-handshake/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In his book, The Left Handshake Hilary St. George Saunders recounts the history of the Boy Scout Movement during the Second World War. 1939-1945. The book is available in PDF format&#xA;It is story of how scouts in occupied countries aided resistance  movements, maintained their troops and provided many public services often at great personal risk.&#xA;Poland, The Warsaw Uprising-&#xA;“After sixty-three days of bitter fighting, the insurrection was crushed, and on the 3 rd October, 1944, Warsaw fell for the second time. It was a cold, grey day, and in a house in Wilcza Street more than a hundred Scouts and Guides had gathered together. They knew it well, for some of them had helped in the hospital which had once been set up there. Now all that remained was a skeleton of scarred brick and mortar. A few were Scoutmasters who had commanded Scout units in the Home Army, but the great majority of that silent band was made up of boys and girls from the age of twelve upwards, all of whom had been heavily engaged in the fighting. They had carried messages, manned first-aid posts and fire parties, looked after homeless children, operated the Scout post office, printed and delivered newspapers, sung songs to divert terrified civilians hidden in the cellars during a bombardment, cooked for the army. There they stood in a semi-circle in the ruins of their city, and of their number forty that morning were decorated with the Cross of Merit and the Cross of Gallantry by the Chief Commissioner.”&#xA;Czechoslovakia-&#xA;“When, a few weeks before the end of the war the Germans carried out a mass migration of prisoners-of-war from east to west Czechoslovakia, Scouts near the German boundary kidnapped some sixty American prisoners-of-war who had arrived in an exhausted and starving condition, hid them in the woods and fed them till their compatriots arrived to find them alive and well, and conversing with their hosts by means of the American Indian sign language.”&#xA;Belgium-&#xA;“In the Liege district fourteen regular members of a Rover Crew, of the average age of twenty-two, set up one of the first information sections. Under cover of their Scouting activities they spied on the enemy and sent frequent reports by radio to the Allies. As the war progressed, they became expert in picking up and hiding supplies dropped to the Resistance by parachute. All these Rovers, of whom half paid for their patriotism with their lives, lived ” a tremendous adventure. ” Six escaped eventually to England, and of these, five joined the parachute troops and the other became a fighter pilot. At one time or another, ten of them were in the hands of the Gestapo, and four in those of the Spanish police. Including the seven who were executed, twelve went to concentration camps. At the end of the war the Minister of National Defence awarded a special decoration to be sewn on the flag of this splendid Troop, a unique distinction of which Belgian Scouts are justly proud.”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What happens when Scouts take over?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/what-happens-when-scouts-take-over/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/what-happens-when-scouts-take-over/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tom Gillard is a Scoutmaster in Tullahoma Tennessee. We struck up a correspondence after he was part of a session about the patrol method I presented over the internet for a group of Scouters attending a Merit Badge University. Over the past couple of months Tom has written to tell me about his experiences applying the patrol method in his Troop.&#xA;Tom is no newcomer to Scouting but he wanted to work towards strengthening his youth leadership. He shares the same reservations and doubts we all have when we really jump off into the deep end and unreservedly invest our youth leaders with real responsibility.&#xA;Here’s Tom’s latest installment – I think you’ll find it inspiring:&#xA;Our plans for this month’s outing changed suddenly leaving one week for the Patrol Leader’s Council to adapt. No sweat for them.  They don’t have the same appreciation of time that us older folks have.&#xA;Anyway we usually have an “advancement weekend” for the newly crossed over Webelos, so this is what they started planning.  The permission slips were taken up on the Monday prior to the outing so at least they knew who was going.  A couple of the older Scouts helped them plan a menu, which I wish I’d seen before I saw the Ramen noodles on Saturday night, but…anyway.&#xA;Equipment check? Almost none. We had 6 of the 9 new Scouts and 10 of the older ones going out.  I was still worried…&#xA;Monday night I sent the SPL an advancement report that outlined what each Scout needed for their next rank. I asked him to give us the most’ bang for the buck’ he could while we were camping.  He came up with a schedule and quite a few of the requirements that are best done while out in the woods.  Not bad…&#xA;No calls from anyone all week.&#xA;Saturday I was actually quite apprehensive.  The acting SPL (the real one couldn’t be there) showed up. I gave him the roster and asked him to start checking them off and when all arrived, get them to the vehicles and prepare to leave.  It worked with just a little questioning on my part.  “How many are we missing?  If we are all here shouldn’t we load up and go?”&#xA;I had most of the older Scouts in my suburban. Between their chatter on the drive to our campsite I asked them to tell me what their mission was this weekend.  One of them piped up; “If the older Scouts hadn’t helped us we wouldn’t be where we are today, so we’re here to help these new Scouts start advancing.”  I thought I should probably stop the car and wipe my teary eyes, but I said, “Good, that’s good!”  The others agreed with him.&#xA;They had said the words but could they dance the dance?  I asked more questions about how they would be doing things during the drive.&#xA;When we arrived I ran though your instructional methods with them, (circle-up, round robin, etc.)  Finally they went on their merry way…&#xA;I sat down to watch with two other ‘seasoned’ ASM’s (they are on board with the idea of the Scouts leading), and 4 ‘new’ dads.  I warned them that, while it may be painful to watch, we were letting the Scouts handle things.&#xA;With little to no prompting the older Scouts put the new Scouts into smaller groups and started instructing. Of course they forgot a lot of what I had told them about instructing earlier but I didn’t care: I was proud that they were taking charge!&#xA;I wandered around casually asking if they needed anything, then returning to my chair. One of the ASM’s was keeping the new dads busy showing them map and compass skills.&#xA;As the day progressed we adults remarked what a good job everyone was doing.  At lunch I let the Scouts know that they were doing a WONDERFUL job.  They had a 2 hour session, 2 hour lunch and then another 2 hour session then free time for the rest of the day.&#xA;On their first camping trip with the troop we have a ceremonial welcome for our new Scouts.  I had asked the older Scouts about doing this. They remembered the ceremony and wanted to do it for the new Scouts. We set out 12 candles down the road to our camp. The candles are lit and the younger scouts are led past. An older Scout is standing at each candle. He gives the Scout sign and repeats his point of the Scout law. When they reach the end of the road the new Scouts arrive at a campfire.  I had each of them pick up a stick and bring it to the campfire. I used your SM minute about sticks&#xA;The new dads were suitably impressed by the ceremony.&#xA;Most importantly I watched 6 new Scouts bond with the older Scouts during the day. The older Scouts accepted them without question and without being compelled to do so.&#xA;I commended the Scouts at every opportunity for how well they carried out the whole weekend.&#xA;I know that the next outing could very well be a complete disaster. But times like these you hope that, in their own teenage way, they are actually getting the message!&#xA;Like I’ve told you before we were around 70% youth led. I knew we could do better and it looks like our older Scouts were really capable of doing this all along. I was just scared to let go completely.  I know they can surprise you when you least expect it, but WOW what a wonderful weekend it was.&#xA;Of course there were the eggs cooked on a stove that was way to hot, the bugs that flew into our supper and the unfortunate spiders that wandered into the tent; as you said endless entertainment!&#xA;Thanks again for the support you are giving me and others!&#xA;YIS, Tom&#xA;Tom’s story is a familiar one. It takes some real courage to put the responsibility for things in the hands of the Scouts. But that’s where the responsibility belongs.&#xA;Tom wasn’t totally comfortable with this – none of us ever really are! We worry and fret over whether the Scouts are catching on. But, time and time again, they step up and surprise us with their skill and competence.&#xA;If you give your Scouts few responsibilities they’ll be a little responsible.&#xA;If you give them more responsibility they’ll be more responsible.&#xA;If you give them complete responsibility they’ll be completely responsible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Baden-Powell’s Outlook</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/baden-powells-outlook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/baden-powells-outlook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;From the introduction:&#xA;For thirty yeas B.-P. contributed to the The Scouter notes and comments under the title &amp;ldquo;The Outlook.&amp;rdquo; The reader turned to these first, for he knew that he would there find encouragement, advice, and inspiration — all written in that very personal style which seemed like conversation. It was in this way that B.-P. trained those who were trying to carry out Scouting for Boys. Even when a training system was begun at Gilwell, these notes continued to be the chief means by which B.-P. could pass on his ideas and suggestions to the great army of Scouters everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Camping’s Top Secrets</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/campings-top-secrets/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/campings-top-secrets/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My first reaction to this title was “yeah, right”. I’ve been a camper all my life spending a thousand or more nights under canvas or on the trail. My camping education started forty years ago with Colin Fletcher’s book ‘The Complete Walker’ and expanded to the classics written by Horace Kephart, Nessmuk, and Bradford Angier. I thought I knew all the tricks until I read ‘Camping’s Top Secrets’.&#xA;Cliff Jacobsen’s collection of techniques and ideas have been tested over many years of guiding canoe trips in northern Canada. Creating a comfortable camp in such unforgiving conditions is no mean feat.  No doubt Jacobsen stands on the shoulders of several generations of guides and outdoorsmen yet Camping’s Top Secrets is full of original and really quite useful information.&#xA;I have certainly learned a great deal from this book and place it among the best outdoor how-to books in my library.&#xA;EXCERPTS&#xA;Storm proofing the Eureka Timberline tent with  a couple of additional guy lines and tie-outs makes a three-season tent into a four-season tent. These same principles can be applied to many tents lending them the stability of much more expensive models.&#xA;Cooking Pots&#xA;Blacken your pot bottoms: Pots that are used on open fires get quite black outside. Some experts suggest that you coat the exposed surfaces with liquid soap or shaving cream so the carbon black will clean easily. The result is an awful mess for the dish-washing crew. I leave pots black (they cook faster and more evenly) and keep them inside a plastic-lined nylon bag between uses.&#xA;Aluma Black, a chemical used to blacken aluminum gun sights and mounts, works wonders on pot bottoms. Just daub the chemical on the pot, allow it to dry, and a rich blue-black color will result. Aluma Black is available at gun shops.&#xA;Camping’s Top Secrets&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Productive Chaos</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/productive-chaos/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/productive-chaos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over time, processes that seek to decrease entropy and create order are valued, but improving them gets more difficult as well. If you&amp;rsquo;re seeking to make the organized more organized, it&amp;rsquo;s a tough row to hoe.&#xA;Far easier and more productive to create productive chaos, to interrupt, re-create, produce, invent and redefine.&#xA;Seth Godin&#xA;Most of our work as Scoutmasters is like hiking a trail; start here and end up there. But things are not always that simple and organized. It&amp;rsquo;s not always a steady pace forward. We start, stop, regroup, retreat, advance, turn around, sit down, stand still, walk, run, crawl, limp, saunter; but at least most of the time we are doing something.&#xA;There&amp;rsquo;s a fair amount of productive chaos in Scouting (two words not often associated with one another). As a matter of fact we are specialists in productive chaos. Ideally our plans proceed in a straight, well disciplined line but that&amp;rsquo;s hardly ever the case.&#xA;Leadership is interrupting, re-creating, inventing and redefining. Yesterday&amp;rsquo;s plan may not work today. While the destination doesn&amp;rsquo;t change the way we get there does.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study Shows Nature Walks Alleviate ADHD Symptoms</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/study-shows-nature-walks-alleviate-adhd-symptoms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/study-shows-nature-walks-alleviate-adhd-symptoms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This article from the New York Times reports that children with ADHD benefited from short walks in natural settings. I wonder if there are even greater benefits to a weekend in the woods?&#xA;A small study conducted at the University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign looked at how the environment influenced a child’s concentration skills. The researchers evaluated 17 children with attention deficit hyperactivity disorder, who all took part in three 20-minute walks in a park, a residential neighborhood and a downtown area.&#xA;After each walk, the children were given a standard test… The study found that children were able to focus better after the “green” walks compared to walks in other settings.&#xA;Although the study is small, the data support several earlier studies suggesting that natural settings influence psychological health. In 2004, a survey of parents of 450 children found that “green” outdoor activities reduced A.D.H.D. symptoms more than activities in other settings.&#xA;Despite the small size, the study is important because it involves an objective test of attention and doesn’t rely on children’s or parents’ impressions. During the walks, all of the children were unmedicated — participants who normally took medications to control their A.D.H.D. symptoms stayed off the drugs on the days of the walks.&#xA;The researchers found that a “dose of nature” worked as well or better than a dose of medication on the child’s ability to concentrate.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Four Roles of Mentors</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/the-four-roles-of-mentors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/the-four-roles-of-mentors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mentoring often goes on unnoticed in Scouting because it is so integral to the process. Here is a succinct look at four elements of mentoring. I find these particularly helpful in balancing my approach to working with our Scouts.&#xA;Recognition. “I don’t know of any test or software program that can make the kinds of subtle, personal distinctions that differentiate an interest from a burning passion. A mentor who has already found the Element in a particular discipline can do precisely that. Mentors recognize the spark of interest or delight and can help an individual drill down to the specific components of the discipline that match that individual’s capacity and passion.”&#xA;Encouragement. “Mentors lead us to believe that we can achieve something that seemed improbable or impossible to us before we met them.”&#xA;Facilitating. “Mentors can help lead us toward our Element by offering us advice and techniques, paving the way for us, and even allowing us to falter a bit while standing by to help us recover and learn from our mistakes.”&#xA;Stretching. “Effective mentors push us past what we see as our limits. Much as they don’t allow us to succumb to self-doubt, the also prevent us from doing less with our lives than we can.”&#xA;From&#xA;The Element: How Finding Your Passion Changes Everything by Ken Robinson,&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Parents We Mean To Be</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/the-parents-we-mean-to-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/the-parents-we-mean-to-be/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Father of three child and family psychologist Richard Weissbourd teaches at Harvard&amp;rsquo;s Kennedy School of Government and School of Education. His new book &amp;lsquo;The Parents We Mean To Be&amp;rsquo; argues  that parents have a much greater influence on their children&amp;rsquo;s moral lives than peers or popular culture.&#xA;Serving as a Scoutmaster  involves a fair amount o exposure to many different styles of parenting and I believe that Weissbourd&amp;rsquo;s ideas form a solid approach. He discusses that preoccupation with achievement, superficial happiness and attempts to befriend our children often misdirect a parent&amp;rsquo;s attempt to develop moral, balanced, functioning human beings. I was drawn to his ideas because Scouting meets Weissbourd&amp;rsquo;s prescription for good parenting. His book is available at Amazon&#xA;“What matters most as a parent is not whether my wife and I are ‘perfect’&#xA;role models or how much we talk about values, but the hundreds of ways&#xA;– as living, breathing, imperfect human beings—we influence our&#xA;children in the complex, messy relationships we have with them day to&#xA;day.”&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Many parents are narrowly focused on their children’s happiness and&#xA;believe that happiness and self-esteem are at the root of morality. We&#xA;may be the first generation of parents in history who hold that belief.&#xA;We think that a child who feels good, and who feels good about herself,&#xA;is more likely to be good. Historically, parents have thought that&#xA;suffering, burdens, and sacrifices were an important basis of morality,&#xA;that through suffering children learned empathy. But in many day-to-day&#xA;ways, we as parents place our children’s happiness above their caring&#xA;about others. We are too quick to let our kids write off friends they&#xA;find annoying. We fail to insist that they return phone calls from&#xA;friends, or give credit to other children for their achievements, or&#xA;reach out to friendless children at the playground. Or we fail to&#xA;interrupt our children when they talk too much when they’re around&#xA;other kids or adults.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Morality is comprised of many attributes—courage,&#xA;honesty, kindness, a sense of justice, moral reasoning, etc.—and there&#xA;are many different ways that adults can promote these qualities. We can&#xA;model appropriate moral behavior, help our children register kindness&#xA;and unkindness in the world around them, define clearly their&#xA;responsibilities toward others, listen responsively to their moral&#xA;dilemmas and questions, hold them to high moral standards, and develop&#xA;in them from an early age the habit of attending to and caring about&#xA;others. We can do much more to emphasize kindness rather than&#xA;happiness—rather than telling our kids all the time that the most&#xA;important thing is that they’re happy, it wouldn’t hurt to tell them&#xA;that the most important thing is that they’re kind.&#xA;But if I could give just one piece of advice to adults, it would be to&#xA;focus not on children’s happiness or self-esteem but on their&#xA;maturity&#xA;.&#xA;Maturity, including the ability to manage destructive feelings, to&#xA;balance and coordinate our needs with those of others, to receive&#xA;feedback constructively, to be reflective and self-critical—to fairly&#xA;and generously assess our behavior is the basis of both morality and&#xA;lasting well-being. It is these capacities that enable children and&#xA;adults to appreciate others despite conflicts of interest and&#xA;differences in perspective, to adhere to important principles and to&#xA;engage in sturdy, meaningful relationships and endeavors that create&#xA;lasting self-worth.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Many of us have unacknowledged fears about our children not achieving&#xA;at a high level. And because of these unrecognized fears, many of us&#xA;are quietly organizing our children’s lives around achievement and&#xA;sending inconsistent and hypocritical messages to our kids. The kids we&#xA;interviewed talked about these hypocrisies. Kids would point out, for&#xA;instance, that their parents would tell them they don’t care how much&#xA;they achieve and then pay jaw-dropping amounts of money for SAT-prep&#xA;courses. When parents tell teenagers to achieve at a high level so they&#xA;“can have options,” teenagers sniff out that their parents are talking&#xA;only about certain options—it’s not really okay for them to be&#xA;beauticians or firefighters, for example. These hypocrisies undermine&#xA;us as moral mentors. We should make achievement for our children one&#xA;theme in the larger composition of a life, and we need to understand&#xA;our own feelings better so we can have more authentic conversations&#xA;with our children about their achievements.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;&amp;ldquo;Yet the reality is that every stage of adult life can bring new moral&#xA;strengths and weaknesses, and that these changes have profound&#xA;consequences for children’s moral growth. “There is nothing noble in&#xA;being superior to somebody else,” the civil rights leader Whitney Young&#xA;said. “The only real nobility is in being superior to your former&#xA;self.” Parenting can spur either great moral growth or regression—think&#xA;of the large number of fathers who abandon their children. We send a&#xA;smug and false message to our children when we suggest that morality&#xA;simply arrives with adulthood and that all they have to do is imitate&#xA;our moral qualities and values. If we parents work at it, we can&#xA;greatly increase our own capacity for fairness, caring, and idealism,&#xA;and our developing morality will be deeply interwoven with our&#xA;children’s developing morality.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Scouting Party</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/the-scouting-party/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/the-scouting-party/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have spent some memorable hours reading an advance copy of David C. Scott and Brendan Murphy’s new book The Scouting Party; a thoroughly researched, unflinching account of the founding and first decade of the BSA focused on  the lives of Earnest Thompson Seton, Robert Baden-Powell and Daniel Carter Beard. To my knowledge no one has so thoroughly analyzed the events and personalities involved in the founding of the BSA.&#xA;Histories of the BSA’s early years are typically encapsulations that may mention the differences between Seton, Beard and Baden-Powell in passing but The Scouting Party takes these matters up in incredible detail mappings out the troubled relationships of these three men through their letters and writings.&#xA;Rather than legend or hagiography this account is a work of careful reportage leading to a deeper understanding of the resilient and vital ideas created in this maelstrom of personalities.The result is is an inspiring account of ideas too big for any one man’s work. Despite their deep animosities for one another Seton, Powell and Beard ultimately created a remarkable organization. Clearly such an expansive vision would never have been realized without this dynamic tension.&#xA;The calculating hand of our first National Scout Executive, James West, and the somewhat mercenary machinations of publisher William D. Boyce weave through the narrative; two men who were crucial in bringing the work of far more visionary men to a practical reality.&#xA;We learn that Seton first envisioned the key concepts central to the basis of Scouting, Baden-Powell’s disciplined pragmatism was vital in bringing Seton’s somewhat woolly, inaccessible vision, to reality and Beard’s contributions were important to popularizing the movement in its formative years.&#xA;Each of these wildly divergent personalities were all key in forming the BSA as we know it. Having a measured, scholarly look at them in their own words as they forged this organization is incredibly valuable to our collective future. As we continue work to bring the promises of Scouting to reality we will encounter similar conflicts of style, personality and ideas. We can overcome these challenges and continue to weave together a vital, relevant, movement that answers the needs of the future while remaining firmly rooted in the vision of its creation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Troop Based High Adventure Programs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/troop-based-high-adventure-programs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/troop-based-high-adventure-programs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Philmont, Seabase and Northern Tier are the three most familiar national High Adventure Bases, there are dozens of other Council Based Programs.&#xA;Thousands of Scouts participate in and enjoy the big three high adventure bases each year. I have colleagues in Scouting who recommend them highly. At the other end of the high- adventure spectrum are the Troop and Crew-based programs that explore less known territory.&#xA;Our rationale for building our own high adventure program is based of a few logistic and philosophic criteria;&#xA;Time and Money&#xA;Most of the established programs involve air travel and substantial ground fees at the base itself. From our Mid-Atlantic  location the cost of participating is over $1000.00. Each also requires twelve or fourteen days including travel time. In comparison our trips cost approximately half as much and run from early Friday to the following Saturday night – consuming only  six vacation days.&#xA;Roller Coaster Vs. Bike&#xA;Most of the national programs are preplanned, preset programs that involve a minimal amount of flexibility. The dates, activities, equipment and routes are usually predetermined. There is also a good deal of competition for the best routes and times. I liken this to lining up for a roller coaster ride; buy your ticket and get in line. Troop-based high-high adventure trips are more flexible; more like getting on your bike and heading out for a ride. Not that the roller coaster isn&amp;rsquo;t fun or challenging – it is just a different approach.&#xA;What does it take to put together a Troop based High Adventure Program? It is not so difficult as you may think. This week I&amp;rsquo;ll be writing about our experience with the process- tomorrow we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss how to get started.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wilderness First Aid</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/wilderness-first-aid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/wilderness-first-aid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This weekend I completed my 16 hours of Wilderness First Aid training. Crews bound for Philmont this summer must have “… at a least one person, preferably two, (either an advisor or a youth participant) in each crew be currently certified in American Red Cross Wilderness First Aid or the equivalent and CPR from the American Heart Association, the American Red Cross or the equivalent.&amp;quot;&#xA;Our three high adventure crews are headed north to Algonquin Provincial Park in Ontario Canada this summer rather than west to Philmont but we will be in a similarly remote situation and thought it wise that we should observe the same precautions. Wilderness First Aid  prepares us for emergencies when help is some hours away.&#xA;Focused on the the prevention, recognition and response of illness and injury the course builds on basic first aid skills. Much of the time was devoted to learning and practicing how to assess, stabilize and monitor injuries. Trainees don&amp;rsquo;t leave the course as EMT&amp;rsquo;s or anything close but they should be capable of applying some advanced skills while waiting for help to arrive.  I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be surprised if WFA training became a requirement to obtain a tour permit for any Scout activity where emergency response time was four or more hours in length.&#xA;Safety on any Scouting adventure depends on good leadership. Good leadership requires a commitment to training. If your Scout Council has an active High Adventure Program they have probably arranged to offer WFA training.&#xA;Wilderness First Aid article in Scouting Magazine&#xA;Wilderness Safety Council website (courses offered in Mid Atlantic states)&#xA;NOTE That while the Philmont policy quoted above specifically references  &amp;lsquo;American Red Cross Wilderness First Aid&amp;rsquo; I was unable to find any such training on their website.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>What’s more important; Effort or Results?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/whats-more-important-effort-or-results/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/whats-more-important-effort-or-results/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Badges and awards are results; but Scoutmaster&amp;rsquo;s know it&amp;rsquo;s more important to recognize effort.&#xA;In his book Shine Psychiatrist Ned Hallowell concludes that acknowledgment of effort provides vital encouragement, motivation and inspires greater confidence, but also  promotes moral behavior;&#xA;“When a  person feels recognized and connected to the larger group, she knows  viscerally, not just intellectually, that she has made a contribution  others value. Not only does this motivate her to do more and try harder,  but it instills a desire to look out for the larger group…. It leads a  person to do the right thing even when no one is looking.”&#xA;Showing appreciation is part of a process he calls ‘shine&amp;rsquo;;&#xA;Recognize effort, not just results.&#xA;Of course, you want the results, but if you recognize ongoing effort, results will more likely ensue.&#xA;Cheerleading works.&#xA;Notice details.&#xA;Generic acknowledgment pales next to specific recognition.&#xA;Provide recognition in person.&#xA;Make others look good, not bad.&#xA;Recognition is a powerful tool to preserve self-esteem.&#xA;Acknowledge people’s existence! say hello, give  a nod of the head, a high five, a smile in passing.&#xA;Tap into the power of positive feedback. Remember that positive feedback often consolidates gains better than learning from mistakes.&#xA;Monitor progress. Performance improves when a person’s progress toward a goal is monitored regularly.&#xA;Establish the habit of recognition of hard work and progress.&#xA;Bring in the marginalized people.&#xA;In most organizations,  about 15 percent of people feel unrecognized, misunderstood, devalued,  and generally disconnected. Not only is recognition good for that 15  percent to help them feel valued, it is good for the other 85 percent as  well, as it boots the positive energy across the organization.&#xA;I am not really cut out to be a cheerleader so I have to work at this sort of thing. I don&amp;rsquo;t engage in the kind of empty, reactive, insincere praise that is often reduced to catchphrases. I do look for honest expressions of effort and take every opportunity to build on the least expression of initiative in my Scouts by recognizing them in front of their peers.&#xA;We know that a positive reaction to effort, even when it falls short of the mark, is important. Negative reactions tend to make Scouts defensive and reluctant to try again. What&amp;rsquo;s important is not just to mouth words of encouragement but to actually be encouraging.&#xA;Scouts who get honest recognition for honest effort go on to achieve big things.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Can Scouts Use Power Tools?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/can-scouts-use-power-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/can-scouts-use-power-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Assistant Scoutmaster Michael from Troop 2000 in Brockton Mass. asks:&#xA;Can Scouts use power tools? I’m confused because I’ve been told they can’t yet the BSA guidelines say they can.&#xA;My other problem is that these guidelines are completely void of any specific information as to which tools are allowed and which ones are not.&#xA;We can find the answer to this perennial question in The Guide to Safe Scouting&#xA;As you note anyone registered as a Boy Scout (10 1/2 years old and older) or Venture is permitted to use power tools. This isn’t my opinion – it is BSA policy in black and white.&#xA;The guide is silent on which power tools because each of us is expected to use our experience and common sense in deciding which     boys use which tools. I am a carpenter by trade, so I have some     familiarity with the subject. I’d have no problem allowing most     11-year-old Scouts operate a drill, but I wouldn’t want most of     them to use a circular saw. Then again there are some     seventeen-year-old Scouts who worry me when they use a butter knife     much less a power tool.&#xA;Almost every merit badge merit badge requirement I can think of can     be completed with hand tools – a bit slower, yes, but they can be     completed. You’ll also note that they have a safety element built     in. Here’s the first requirement for woodworking MB:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
