<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Safety on Scoutmastercg.com Archive</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/safety/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Safety on Scoutmastercg.com Archive</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/safety/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Can Scouts Use Power Tools?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/can-scouts-use-power-tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/can-scouts-use-power-tools/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Assistant Scoutmaster Michael from Troop 2000 in Brockton Mass. asks:&#xA;Can Scouts use power tools? I’m confused because I’ve been told they can’t yet the BSA guidelines say they can.&#xA;My other problem is that these guidelines are completely void of any specific information as to which tools are allowed and which ones are not.&#xA;We can find the answer to this perennial question in The Guide to Safe Scouting&#xA;As you note anyone registered as a Boy Scout (10 1/2 years old and older) or Venture is permitted to use power tools. This isn’t my opinion – it is BSA policy in black and white.&#xA;The guide is silent on which power tools because each of us is expected to use our experience and common sense in deciding which     boys use which tools. I am a carpenter by trade, so I have some     familiarity with the subject. I’d have no problem allowing most     11-year-old Scouts operate a drill, but I wouldn’t want most of     them to use a circular saw. Then again there are some     seventeen-year-old Scouts who worry me when they use a butter knife     much less a power tool.&#xA;Almost every merit badge merit badge requirement I can think of can     be completed with hand tools – a bit slower, yes, but they can be     completed. You’ll also note that they have a safety element built     in. Here’s the first requirement for woodworking MB:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
