<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Northern-Tier on Scoutmastercg.com Archive</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/northern-tier/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Northern-Tier on Scoutmastercg.com Archive</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/northern-tier/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Troop Based High Adventure Programs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/troop-based-high-adventure-programs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/troop-based-high-adventure-programs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Philmont, Seabase and Northern Tier are the three most familiar national High Adventure Bases, there are dozens of other Council Based Programs.&#xA;Thousands of Scouts participate in and enjoy the big three high adventure bases each year. I have colleagues in Scouting who recommend them highly. At the other end of the high- adventure spectrum are the Troop and Crew-based programs that explore less known territory.&#xA;Our rationale for building our own high adventure program is based of a few logistic and philosophic criteria;&#xA;Time and Money&#xA;Most of the established programs involve air travel and substantial ground fees at the base itself. From our Mid-Atlantic  location the cost of participating is over $1000.00. Each also requires twelve or fourteen days including travel time. In comparison our trips cost approximately half as much and run from early Friday to the following Saturday night – consuming only  six vacation days.&#xA;Roller Coaster Vs. Bike&#xA;Most of the national programs are preplanned, preset programs that involve a minimal amount of flexibility. The dates, activities, equipment and routes are usually predetermined. There is also a good deal of competition for the best routes and times. I liken this to lining up for a roller coaster ride; buy your ticket and get in line. Troop-based high-high adventure trips are more flexible; more like getting on your bike and heading out for a ride. Not that the roller coaster isn&amp;rsquo;t fun or challenging – it is just a different approach.&#xA;What does it take to put together a Troop based High Adventure Program? It is not so difficult as you may think. This week I&amp;rsquo;ll be writing about our experience with the process- tomorrow we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss how to get started.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
