<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Program-Health on Scoutmastercg.com Archive</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/program-health/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Program-Health on Scoutmastercg.com Archive</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/program-health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Looking Ahead - Program Health</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/looking-ahead-program-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/looking-ahead-program-health/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Fifth and final entry  in a series of thoughts about&#xA;looking ahead&#xA;.&#xA;Do we meet key indicators of effectively presenting our program?&#xA;The quality unit award (now the&#xA;centennial quality unit award&#xA;) has been the generally accepted standard for assessing unit program. Quality unit metrics do give some indications of the health of the program but we should take a closer look.&#xA;Quality unit metrics report adult leader training, youth recruitment and retention, parent participation, youth advancement, outdoor program participation, program planning. Meeting these indicators is somewhat like having a pulse – the unit is alive and kicking. Problem is a unit can meet these criterion with a program led and administered by adult leadership as well as one administered by youth leadership.&#xA;My choice of indicators would be a little different:&#xA;Patrol System&#xA;Patrols plan, purchase and prepare their own meals on camp outs.&#xA;The patrol leader was elected by the patrol.&#xA;Patrol leaders routinely sign off rank requirements.&#xA;Youth Leadership&#xA;Patrol leader&amp;rsquo;s council meets regularly&#xA;Senior patrol leader is elected by Scouts&#xA;Youth plan and present weekly Troop meetings and outings&#xA;Troops that meet these key indicators will almost certainly meet or exceed the quality unit metrics but not necessarily the other way round.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
