<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Patrol Method on Scoutmastercg.com Archive</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/patrol-method/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Patrol Method on Scoutmastercg.com Archive</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/patrol-method/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Model Scout Outing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/model-scout-outing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/model-scout-outing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;“Scouting is Outing” and any lively, active Troop has an out-of-doors overnight experience planned every month of the year. Here’s a model of a typical outing that capitalizes on youth leadership and the Patrol Method.&#xA;Preparation&#xA;After the Patrol Leader’s Council (PLC) has developed a schedule of events for the year Scouts are detailed to set up the particulars of the trip. A few of the logistics are attended to by the adults ( securing campsites, various registrations etc.) but the PLC does the vast  majority of planning.&#xA;Patrols select a grubmaster for the trip who plans, purchases, packs and prepares their meals for the outing. Patrol Scribes collect fees and permission slips, the Patrol Quartermaster checks over the gear they will need and the Patrol leader administers all of these preparations.&#xA;The Senior Patrol Leader (SPL) and his cohorts form a transportation plan and oversee the preparations of the Patrols. The Troop Scribe collects money and permission slips from Patrol Scribes and develops a Troop roster for the outing. The Troop Quartermaster oversees the Patrol Quartermasters in preparing their gear. The SPL creates a schedule of activities for the outing.&#xA;Troop meetings leading up to the outing discuss any special skills or preparations for the trip. Ample time is scheduled for Patrols to complete their preparations.&#xA;Friday Night&#xA;The SPL and Patrol Leaders see that the Scouts have the proper personal gear and draw their Patrol and Troop gear from the Quartermaster, see that it is all packed properly, load everything up and move out.&#xA;Once they arrive at the campsite the SPL surveys the ground and assigns areas for each Patrol. He does his best to see that Patrols camp far enough apart to operate independently and that the adults are billeted far enough away to allow the Troop to function properly.&#xA;Before they head off to bed the PLC meets and reviews the schedule for the next day.&#xA;Saturday&#xA;The SPL and Patrol leaders get everyone up at the specified hour and breakfast is prepared. Patrols cook on their own and the Adults (who have planned and packed their own food) observe from a respectful distance.&#xA;Once breakfast is cleared away the day begins. The SPL and Patrol Leaders lead the Scouts through whatever activity is the order of the day. Adults may be invited to offer instruction (rarely) or asked to lend some oversight if the nature of the activity demands it. Otherwise the adults are pursing their own activities away from the Scouts.&#xA;Lunch and dinner happen much like breakfast as the day wears on.&#xA;The entire Troop gathers together for the first time Saturday evening. It may be a brief review of the day’s events, a campfire, a cracker-barrel or similar function.&#xA;Before everyone retires the SPL reviews Sunday’s activities with the PLC.&#xA;Sunday&#xA;Breakfast again prepared by the Patrols. It may be time to pack up, or to pursue some activity before returning home. On returning the SPL oversees the return of gear with the Quartermaster and Patrol Quartermasters.&#xA;After Action&#xA;The PLC meets to discuss the outing and what improvements can be made to their preparations or implementation. The gear is checked and cleaned if needed and the whole process is ready to begin again.&#xA;This model is just that, a model. It is based on the idea that Scouts must be given a very wide latitude to operate independent of adult interference yet with appropriate oversight. There is very little that the Scouts cannot do for themselves and they should be encouraged to do as much as they can manage.&#xA;Scouts cook on their own, camp on their own and pursue their activities on their own. Adults may be invited to participate actively, but unless they are they keep a respectful distance. How far distant? Ideally out of earshot and out of sight but close enough to be called upon if required.&#xA;Scouting is not a father or mother and son activity, not a family outing. Scouting happens when the Scouts lead themselves. When they are given autonomy and trust they respond by being responsible.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
