<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>High Adventure on Scoutmastercg.com Archive</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/high-adventure/</link>
    <description>Recent content in High Adventure on Scoutmastercg.com Archive</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/high-adventure/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Troop Based High Adventure Programs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/troop-based-high-adventure-programs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/troop-based-high-adventure-programs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Philmont, Seabase and Northern Tier are the three most familiar national High Adventure Bases, there are dozens of other Council Based Programs.&#xA;Thousands of Scouts participate in and enjoy the big three high adventure bases each year. I have colleagues in Scouting who recommend them highly. At the other end of the high- adventure spectrum are the Troop and Crew-based programs that explore less known territory.&#xA;Our rationale for building our own high adventure program is based of a few logistic and philosophic criteria;&#xA;Time and Money&#xA;Most of the established programs involve air travel and substantial ground fees at the base itself. From our Mid-Atlantic  location the cost of participating is over $1000.00. Each also requires twelve or fourteen days including travel time. In comparison our trips cost approximately half as much and run from early Friday to the following Saturday night – consuming only  six vacation days.&#xA;Roller Coaster Vs. Bike&#xA;Most of the national programs are preplanned, preset programs that involve a minimal amount of flexibility. The dates, activities, equipment and routes are usually predetermined. There is also a good deal of competition for the best routes and times. I liken this to lining up for a roller coaster ride; buy your ticket and get in line. Troop-based high-high adventure trips are more flexible; more like getting on your bike and heading out for a ride. Not that the roller coaster isn&amp;rsquo;t fun or challenging – it is just a different approach.&#xA;What does it take to put together a Troop based High Adventure Program? It is not so difficult as you may think. This week I&amp;rsquo;ll be writing about our experience with the process- tomorrow we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss how to get started.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Wilderness First Aid</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/wilderness-first-aid/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/wilderness-first-aid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This weekend I completed my 16 hours of Wilderness First Aid training. Crews bound for Philmont this summer must have “… at a least one person, preferably two, (either an advisor or a youth participant) in each crew be currently certified in American Red Cross Wilderness First Aid or the equivalent and CPR from the American Heart Association, the American Red Cross or the equivalent.&amp;quot;&#xA;Our three high adventure crews are headed north to Algonquin Provincial Park in Ontario Canada this summer rather than west to Philmont but we will be in a similarly remote situation and thought it wise that we should observe the same precautions. Wilderness First Aid  prepares us for emergencies when help is some hours away.&#xA;Focused on the the prevention, recognition and response of illness and injury the course builds on basic first aid skills. Much of the time was devoted to learning and practicing how to assess, stabilize and monitor injuries. Trainees don&amp;rsquo;t leave the course as EMT&amp;rsquo;s or anything close but they should be capable of applying some advanced skills while waiting for help to arrive.  I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be surprised if WFA training became a requirement to obtain a tour permit for any Scout activity where emergency response time was four or more hours in length.&#xA;Safety on any Scouting adventure depends on good leadership. Good leadership requires a commitment to training. If your Scout Council has an active High Adventure Program they have probably arranged to offer WFA training.&#xA;Wilderness First Aid article in Scouting Magazine&#xA;Wilderness Safety Council website (courses offered in Mid Atlantic states)&#xA;NOTE That while the Philmont policy quoted above specifically references  &amp;lsquo;American Red Cross Wilderness First Aid&amp;rsquo; I was unable to find any such training on their website.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
