<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mentoring on Scoutmastercg.com Archive</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/mentoring/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mentoring on Scoutmastercg.com Archive</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/mentoring/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Four Roles of Mentors</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/the-four-roles-of-mentors/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Apr 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/2011/04/the-four-roles-of-mentors/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Mentoring often goes on unnoticed in Scouting because it is so integral to the process. Here is a succinct look at four elements of mentoring. I find these particularly helpful in balancing my approach to working with our Scouts.&#xA;Recognition. “I don’t know of any test or software program that can make the kinds of subtle, personal distinctions that differentiate an interest from a burning passion. A mentor who has already found the Element in a particular discipline can do precisely that. Mentors recognize the spark of interest or delight and can help an individual drill down to the specific components of the discipline that match that individual’s capacity and passion.”&#xA;Encouragement. “Mentors lead us to believe that we can achieve something that seemed improbable or impossible to us before we met them.”&#xA;Facilitating. “Mentors can help lead us toward our Element by offering us advice and techniques, paving the way for us, and even allowing us to falter a bit while standing by to help us recover and learn from our mistakes.”&#xA;Stretching. “Effective mentors push us past what we see as our limits. Much as they don’t allow us to succumb to self-doubt, the also prevent us from doing less with our lives than we can.”&#xA;From&#xA;The Element: How Finding Your Passion Changes Everything by Ken Robinson,&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
